Never forget why you are the church.
Go ahead and turn your Bible to Romans 12 just to
give you comfort that will be there.
But anyway, um, sometimes when the with
the internet that we have, we aren't able to live stream, but that does not change the
fact that we are recording it, and we're able to post it,
um, later on in our in our player, on the
app and on the website.
So if you missed last week or if you missed a week, you
know, prior to that, or if you're trying to watch it home right now and it's
not working, don't worry, don't panic, we will get that out to you.
It'll actually be a perfected recording, not
that anything changes that I say, but along the lines of the sound and the quality of it.
So, but we are in Romans 12 this morning.
And we move to the next portion of text within our
theme, the impact of the gospel.
Now, I cannot emphasize enough that the
gospel of Jesus Christ impacts every
part of a believer's life.
Listen, the gospel of Jesus impacts
everything that we say, we do, and we are.
Every part of our life is impacted by Christ.
Now we have taken several weeks to look over the
impact of the gospel in particular in our ministry.
Just to review that really quickly.
In Romans 12, verse 6 through 8.
It says this, having them gifts differing according to the
grace that is given to us, whether prophecy
let us prophesy according to the proportion of faith
or ministry, let us wait on our ministering, or he
that teacheth on teaching, or he that exhorteth on
exhortation, he that giveth, let him do it with simplicity,
he that ruleth with diligence, he that showeth mercy
with cheerfulness.
Paul is basically telling the believers in
Rome that whatever your spiritual gift is, use it.
Now understand something, the way that works is,
if you are a born again believer, you have a gift.
Therefore, Paul is telling you today, use it.
Do something for the Lord with the gift
that he's given you to do something for him.
Amen.
And so listen, you look at a dying church.
1st off, we serve a living God.
Amen?
There is no such thing.
The church will never die.
We are the bride of Christ.
He has us.
He sealed us.
He keeps us.
But if you look at a church that stopped growing.
That stop ministering, that stop making impact.
That's not God's fault.
He's gifted every believer in that church with the ability for the supernatural.
It's our fault for not utilizing the gifts that we get that we get.
Now, again, you want to be a part of a thriving and growing church.
Get the people to look at serving in the church differently.
It's not that we have to, but rather we get to because
we've been gifted.
This morning, we move on to the next part of our life that
the gospel impacts.
And this is one that's very important, just like the last.
By the way, I just want to say this.
Whenever I say something is very important, it's all important.
Amen.
But just as preacher talks, sometimes I say it.
I don't know why, but this is very important, amen?
But the impact of the gospel in our relationships.
The impact of the gospel in our relationships.
Let's pray, Father, I thank you, Lord, that you are the same God.
God, I thank you that when
Paul was writing to the believers in Rome, God,
that same gospel, that same exhortation,
that same encouragement, that same truth is true today
because you are the same God.
So God, I pray, Lord, that we take heed to your word, God.
And I pray that we don't think it is for somebody else, but
God, I pray that we understand it is for us.
And it's in Jesus name, pray.
Amen.
The impact of the gospel in our relationships.
The remaining portion of Romans is written a little different than
the previous verses, or at least in Romans 12.
It is almost as if Paul writes out a list of proverbs for us to live by.
Paul here is listening out exhortations and
commands that we are to pay attention to
and live out in our lives.
Every single one of them has to do with
our relationship with others.
Before we even get to the text today, though, there
is an important truth that we have to understand to kind
of build the foundation and framework for this text.
First off, God created us to be
relational.
Now, what that means is God created
you to be relational, just like he created me
to be relational.
The Bible tells us that we are created in the image of God.
But often we forget the language used in Genesis
one, verse 26, and God's that led us.
Make man in our image after our
likeness.
See, there's a relationship there.
God reveals in the 1st chapter of the Bible that we are created in
the likeness of the perfectly triune God.
There is an inherent relational nature in our
creation.
If you keep reading in Genesis, you'll see this need for relationship
intensifying.
Genesis 2, verse 18, and Lord God said, it
is not good that the man should be alone.
I will make him and help me for him.
It's when he created Eve.
See, family was created by God in that moment.
God expanded his creation of
family with his command to be fruitful and multiply.
Yes, it is a command.
Genesis 128, and God blessed them, and God said unto them,
be fruitful and multiply, and replenish
the earth and subdue it, and have dominion over the fish of the
sea, and over the foul, the air, and over every living thing that moveth upon
the earth.
Here we see not just relationship, but responsibility
within our relationship.
Now, I know what you're thinking.
Well, as long as it's just me and my family, I'm fine.
Well, in our culture,
we have excused this introvert versus extrovert
personality difference to an extent that
just to be frank with you hinders the fellowship of the church.
Y'all with me?
Listen, I'm an extrovert.
Would you agree with me?
Amen.
I have no pro.
People say, I don't like crowds.
I don't understand that.
I love me some crowd.
Amen?
We went to New York City back before it was crazy, crazy.
And man, it was like 2017.
It was at Christmas time.
And dude, we were like bumping people and having, this is literally
how it, if everyone was taken away.
And you just saw how we were walking, it would look like this.
I mean, literally, that's how many people, man, I'm just, I'm loving it.
Like, I love the airport, right?
I don't like flying, but I like the airport because you can watch people.
I like going to the mall.
There's nothing like seeing a full Opry Mills.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
When you go there and it's empty and it's like everyone's just sad to be there.
Man, I like the days when everything was full.
I like crowds.
I'm an extrovert.
Listen, we have a sign in our house that says, hey, you're welcome to stay, but be gone by nine.
I didn't put that up.
Heather put that up.
Listen, I don't care how long you stay.
You understand what I'm saying?
But you better be gone by 9 because Heather said so.
But either way, listen, then you have introverts, right?
They don't really like crowds.
They don't necessarily mesh with that kind of situation.
I want you to know something.
Yes, God knew what he was doing when he created you, but
your personality does not change his truth.
You understand what I'm saying to you this morning?
See, understand, God created family, but he also created community.
We have talked about this in death, but the primary community
for a New Testament believer is the local church.
God has never called us to isolation.
Listen, we can have a big old long conversation about the
monks and all the people that go up in the mountains and who
are they sharing the gospel with?
Nobody.
Listen, we put this thing of like, well, hey, listen,
I'm just going to be alone and serve the Lord alone.
That's not how he called us to be.
As a matter of fact, if you took Jeremiah, the weeping prophet.
Why was he weeping?
Because he was the only one in Israel at the time that
was really caring about what God said.
I guarantee you, if you said, you know what, Jeremiah, we'll give you a community
of believers that believe just like you do.
You know what he's due?
He stopped weeping and he'd start communing communitying.
Amen.
I don't know what that word even is.
What it's a new one, Carlos.
That's good.
But what I'm trying to say is this.
We got to be careful.
God has not caused isolation.
For someone to justify being mean-spirited, rude, and hateful
towards others by claiming, well, I'm just that's just my personality.
It's not that's not in line with biblical integrity.
Being a jerk is not a personality.
It's a sin.
So
if our relationship towards one another is important, then
it is a good idea to know what God says about it.
So we're going to read this in this text in its entirety.
It's going to be quite a few verses, but we're going to take these exhortations
and commands one by one.
Amen?
And so if you're in Romans chapter 12, starting in
verse nine, someone say, read.
Let love be without the simulation.
Abhor that which is evil, cleave to that which is good.
Be kindly affectionate one to another with brotherly
love, in honor of preferring one another.
Not slothful and business, fervent and spirit.
serving the Lord, rejoicing in hope, patient in tribulation,
continuing instant in prayer, distributing to the necessity
of saints, given the hospitality.
Bless them which persecute you, bless and curse not.
Rejoice with them that do rejoice and weep with them that weep.
Be of the same mind one toward another, mind
not high things, but condescend to men of low estate, be not
wise in your own conceits.
Recompense to a man, ev,
uh recompense to no man, evil for evil, provide things honest
in the sight of all men.
If it be possible, as much as lieth
in you, live peaceably with all men.
Dearly beloved, avenge not yourselves, but rather
give place, but rather give place, and the wrath for it is written, vengeance is mine.
I will repay, saith the Lord.
Therefore, thine enemy hunger, feed him.
If he thirsts, give him drink.
For in doing so, thou shalt heat coals of fire on his head.
Be not overcome of evil, but overcome
evil with good.
Now listen, obviously that's a whole lot, amen?
And there's a few of them in there that are
taken out of context a whole lot as well.
But this morning, we're going to really focus in on verse
9, it says this, let love be without the simulation, abhor
that which is evil, cleave to that which is good.
Now, what does it mean to love without the simulation?
It means literally to love without
hypocrisy.
In other words, love must be sincere.
What does it look like to love without sincerity?
Well, how about when that person you don't get along with comes
up to you and you put on that big smile and you hug
them and let them know that you love them just for when they
walk away, you do this little eye roll thing?
Oh, they're not, I can't stand them.
But you just was a hypocrite in your love just then.
Are y'all with me this morning?
Listen, it's going to be more practical than you like this morning, okay?
Or that's hypocritical love.
Well, when you are gossiping, slandering a fellow brother or sister
in Christ, but to make it look like not sin,
you end each statement with, oh, but I love him to death.
Listen, that's insincere love.
Listen this is stepping on my toes this morning as well.
A flattering tongue is
hypocritical love.
See, church, every single one of us have
been guilty of loving others in hypocrisy, but
what does this do to a congregation?
What does this do to a family of God?
It divides.
It allows resentment to simmer.
It breeds bitterness.
It creates an unstable environment.
It adds awkwardness to serving together.
Now instead of just serving together in love and honoring
each other more than ourselves, all of a sudden we say, well, I'm
not going to work with somebody, or I'm not going to work with that person, but I'll
serve with that person, or I don't like that person, but I'm going to go with,
listen, there's division there.
It's hypocritical love.
If we are to pattern
on love, it must be in the sincere love demonstrated by God.
In Romans 5, verse one through 5, it says this, therefore,
being justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ.
By whom also we have access by faith
into this grace wherein we stand and rejoice in
hope of the glory of God.
And not only so, but we glory and tribulations also, knowing
that tribulation worketh patience and patience, experience and experience,
hope, and look at what verse 5 says, and hope maketh not ashamed.
Why?
Because the love of God is shed abroad in our hearts by the
Holy Ghost, which is given unto us.
Noticed with God's love shed
upon us through the Holy Spirit, what is absent in that situation.
Shame.
Sincere love has no shame.
Let's think about that.
When you love properly, shame's not a part of it.
It is only when love becomes distorted and
sinful and worldly and secular,
the shame become a problem.
We're in the month of June.
I don't know if you know that or not.
By the way, this summer's flying by, is it not?
My goodness gracious.
For a heartbreaking number of people,
this is when they celebrate what is called Pride Month.
Their pride is attached to what
God explicitly calls sin.
The LGPTQ and whatever else
they want to bundle in is not something, hear me, is not
something to be proud about.
It is something to repent of.
And by the way, I need
you to know this, and you probably heard this.
But one of the biggest arguments is, well, this is just how I was born.
Well, guess what?
I was born in sin as well.
That's why God said, you must be born again.
So we have to understand what God's true says.
We cannot excuse what God calls an abomination.
what God calls sin.
But we see here.
How does this relate to verse nine.
Think about love that is sincere compared to love that
is insincere and hypocritical.
What is the defining, separating factor
of hypocritical love, and sincere love?
Well, I'll tell you, it's truth.
When truth is the foundation
of our love, it is sincere.
When truth is not the foundation of our love, it is hypocritical.
When you love someone hypocritically,
you are in reality lying to them about how you really feel.
Remember the example of seeing
someone in the hallway.
Oh, how you doing?
How you been?
I love you so much.
Let's get together.
Y'all ain't never done that?
I've seen y'all do that.
Amen.
But listen, right, that's hypocritical love.
The heart posture.
By the way, I want to do a little point of clarification here.
You might be like, well, they need to get right.
You know, the heart posture needs to change.
is not theirs.
s yours.
See, we so often want
other people to get right while we just stay wrong.
That's not that's not how it works.
It's just not how it works.
So when we play into the devil's scheme of tolerating
and supporting sin for the sake of love, that is not possible
when we are talking about, what we are talking about is sin.
The greatest act of love that this earth has ever witnessed was Jesus
dying on the cross for the sins of the world.
Therefore, the greatest act of love that we can display to
others is sharing the way, the truth and the life.
That is Jesus, right?
We know Jesus is the way.
There is no other way.
I don't care what that professor says.
I don't care what that false prophet or teacher says.
I don't care what that influencer says on social media.
There is no other way to the Father in heaven except through Jesus.
He is the door by which all and whosoever may enter, but he
is the only door Jesus is the way.
Jesus is also the truth.
That means there is only one truth.
By the way, if you don't believe in objective truth,
then you don't believe in truth.
If truth can change and
waver in this and that and with the time, listen, that's not truth.
That's just that's just your opinion.
But there's only one truth.
In a society that peddles the idea that there
is an infinite amount of truth, all dependent on one's
circumstance and perspective, when it comes to eternal matters,
there is only one truth, and that is Jesus.
His word is true.
Jesus is the way Jesus is the truth, but also Jesus is the life.
John 316, for God so loved the world, that
he gave his only begotten son, that whosoever believeth him should not perish,
but have everlasting life.
He is the life.
There is no life other than the life given to us by Christ.
Without him, the Bible says, you and I are dead.
Without any hope.
But you know what the world is doing?
It is slowly but surely making the message of Christ.
what we, and it's a strong language, and we don't like to
talk about it, but it's slowly making the message of Christ,
the truth, hate speech.
Now
all of a sudden we have to be careful with what we say.
There
is legislation being passed right now in certain countries that would make whole
books of the Bible, legally regarded as hate speech.
Me preaching the book of Romans.
will be regarded hate speech.
As a matter of fact, I don't know all
the details and you can go look it up and give me the details if
you want, but in Canada right now, Canada.
In Canada right now, listen, they have legislation to
where you can't quote scripture in certain ways in certain areas
because it's offensive to what's going on in the situation.
Literally, you can go to jail.
So when someone comes up to me and says, preacher, is this wrong?
It doesn't matter what I think about it.
I got to tell what God thinks about it.
They said that's illegal.
Do you understand what the enemy is doing?
If we can take away truth, We can take everything away.
And
by the way, if we take this away, And we've taken truth away.
Church
is not scripture being fulfilled before our very eyes.
Isaiah 520, woe to those who call evil
good and good evil, who substitute darkness for light and
light for darkness, who substitute bitter for sweet and sweet for bitter.
By the way, I want you to know something.
We love to talk about those who want
to get rid of the Bible and want to get rid of truth and all things,
and that's terrible, and it should never happen, and we
got to hold on to the truth.
That's why the Bible says that if we just hide his word in our hearts
that we may not sin, but I can tell you this right now.
There's a whole bunch of people right now in this
very moment holding up this same word of God, but
they're speaking it in hypocrisy.
That
dude in Texas who's running for whatever seat.
I don't know, Tarantino, I think that's a movie maker.
I don't know what his name is, but listen, hey, listen, he's over here.
He will tell you scripture in order to lie.
He'll tell you, well, well, God said
this and he'll use the screen.
But what he's doing is he is loving others,
but without sincerity.
Whether he knows it or
not, he's leading people to hell.
Are y'all with me this morning?
We must love without hypocrisy, even it
means telling the truth when the truth is openly rejected.
But
that brings us to our next truth.
Part of sincere love is loving the right things.
Look at Romans 12, verse 9.
Let love be without hypocrisy, abhor what is evil?
Cling to what is good.
We have 2 words here that we need to understand.
First, we are to abhor what is evil.
That word abhor means
literally to strongly dislike something with
the result of distancing oneself from the thing disliked.
This is the only place this verb
is found in the New Testament.
But it is similar to what Paul says
in 1st Thessalonians 5, verse one.
It says, or 21.
Sorry, it says, prove all things.
Hold fast that which is good.
Abstain from all appearances of evil.
Church, let me ask you something.
How much distance do you put between you
and that which is evil?
Think about everything.
How much distance do you put?
Well, preacher, we can't really get away from this evil world.
You know, God has us in the world for, oh, really?
Interesting how we distance ourselves from everything else we don't like.
When
I do that, you need to be like, do what Carlos just did.
Okay?
Mm, yeah.
Amen.
Think about it for a 2nd though.
Seriously.
We have no problem distancing ourselves
from everything we don't like.
Why?
Because we keep close proximity with that, which we do like.
So what should we have, who?
What should we be distanced?
What should we strongly dislike so that we go away from?
Will we easily talk about the homosexual and transgender issues?
Of course, stay away from that.
But what about issues like fornication?
Drunkenness, a lying tongue.
These are just a few of the evil examples I can give.
Well, they are my friends.
Well, let me ask you, do you love your friends?
And the best thing you can do is distance yourself from them.
And in doing so, you let them know that you're taking sin, seriously.
I don't want to be around someone who's
openly and unashamedly cheating on their spouse.
Hear me.
I cannot have right fellowship with them.
Don't come bragging to me.
Because that's going to cause distance from us.
And from a distance you know what I'm gonna do, that sin, repent.
Listen, I don't want to be around someone who is
constantly murmuring and causing the vision.
We can't have fellowship with one another.
I don't want to be around someone who sleeps around with anyone they can.
I don't want to be with someone who curses and is filthy.
There's no fellowship there.
Preacher, that sounds like a judgmental attitude.
No wonder people don't like coming to church anymore.
Because preachers like you that talk about, you don't want to be
around me when I sin.
Listen to me.
That's not judgment.
That's wisdom.
Understand something.
Sin is contagious, brothers and sisters.
It'll spread in a church and a family faster
than you can, than you can even think.
You play with fire too long, you will get burned.
I cannot risk my fellowship with God or
his saints on the altar of someone's false interpretation of what judgment is.
Let me say that again for you.
I cannot risk my fellowship with God
or his saints on the altar of someone's false interpretation
of judgment.
But for those who believe
that this posture towards that which is evil is
the reason the church is in the state that it's in.
In other words, well, the church is not growing or
the church is not doing, is supposed to be doing because we don't we don't welcome
people in just like they are.
And we preach against their sin and we step
on their toes and we make them uncomfortable.
You know, I'd much rather be uncomfortable in
a nice seat right there, hearing the gospel preached, how it should be in the truth.
Then there's been eternity in hell and torment.
So if I got to make you uncomfortable just
to open your eyes to what God says about it, guess what?
We'll all get uncomfortable.
But
may I offer a counterargument?
The church is in a state that is
in today because we as the people of God, have not distanced
ourselves from evil, but have accepted and tolerated it for too long.
Now, don't hear what I'm not saying.
You got to go to work.
Amen?
Tomorrow, man, you got to go to work.
And you got some evil people in your work.
I don't know.
I'm just making assumptions.
Okay?
The way you gossip about them.
I'm just kidding.
But listen, you got some people in your work.
Right?
You may not have a godly boss.
You may not have godly coworkers.
You understand what I'm saying?
So, so, so what do you do?
Quit your job?
No.
Absolutely not.
But what you don't do is you don't go to the bar after
after work on Friday just because you got invited.
Well, it's a mission opportunity.
The mission opportunity is saying, no, and here's why.
Y'all go have your fun, but I follow Jesus and I can't do that.
I used to do that, but I don't do that anymore because I follow Christ.
There's the mission opportunity.
Not going and getting drunk with your bodies.
Listen,
hey, you might have a family.
that does not love Jesus.
You say, well, I'm just going to up and up and I saw, man, my brain.
I saw a meme yesterday how someone
said, man, I have thought about running away from home way more as an adult than as a kid.
How sad.
Anyway.
But listen, you may not have a godly family.
Your spouse may not know the Lord.
They may be evil.
But here's the thing.
That doesn't mean you just, you just up and up and I'm out of here.
No, what that means is, listen, hey, you follow the Lord and what he says.
You cling to Jesus.
You separate yourself from the evil.
You don't partake in it.
You let them know, listen, this is not who I am anymore.
I love you, but this is not who I am.
I think about Father's Day.
By the way, you say, what does this have to do with Father's Day?
You know, the greatest father.
If you look at how a father should be,
We should put all of our relationships and watch how he operates
in his life and we can mimic it.
That's a good father.
Amen?
That's why when we see how God operates with us, the relationship we has with us.
But I think of my dad, listen, hey, my dad growing up, I had a great childhood.
My dad loved the Lord.
Him and my mom gave their life to Christ together back
at Hillcrest before they even had all the big buildings, when it
was the red carpet and the seats and the chairs and all the things.
My life, the trajectory of my life changed.
But listen, it wasn't like that for him as a kid.
He didn't he
didn't get ministered to as a kid.
He had a dad who did a lot of evil.
He had a mama that was just trying to do her best to
provide for 5 kids.
But listen, he had to deal with that.
But you know what he didn't do?
He didn't excuse it.
and say, well, this is my life.
No.
God changed him.
And guess what?
I don't even know anything about that.
You say, well, you've been guarded.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
My parents have been changed.
Therefore, no matter what happened to them.
They guard me through the truth.
And so therefore, I can know the Lord as well.
Are y'all with me this morning?
Listen, thank God that we don't have to
be bound by just where we are.
Look at where you are as a mission opportunity to
separate yourselves from evil, so you can therefore share the gospel.
Now again, I
believe God is gradually moving away his blessing because we refuse
to move away from sin.
Romans 129.
Let love be without hypocrisy, abhor what is evil.
Now, this verb to abhor actually teaches us
how we are to love.
So in the doing of distancing ourselves from
that which is evil, it actually shows us how we are to
be in relation to the good things.
Look at that.
At poor, what is evil, cling to what is good.
That word cling is the opposite of abhor, right?
So to abhor something means to distance yourself from something.
Kling literally means to join and go near to.
You are going to be close to something.
So make that something good.
Listen, I hear people
all the time talk about church and And they're like,
oh, well, you know, church is just full of hypocrites and church is
is full of judgmental people.
And, man, back when I went to church,
I didn't like the way it was run and someone hurt my
feelings and this and that and that and this.
Let me just tell you something.
You know what's good about church?
All that can be true.
But God is still good.
You understand what I'm saying?
It doesn't matter our weakness.
He is strong.
Listen, if you think the Cedar Girl Baptist Church is perfect,
then you ain't been here long enough, or
you got your head in the sand.
You understand what I'm saying?
Trust me, hang out with me for a day.
You understand not everyone's perfect.
But you know what?
We're not perfect, but he is.
And so as long as we have a central goal to serve
him and to live for him.
And not only that, but to serve each other in that sincere love.
Listen, we can get past the speed bumps.
We can get past the conflict and the tension.
We can get past when the enemy tries to throw a stone in what's going on.
We can get past it.
Why?
Because we love each other as God has told us to.
See, and again, it's
not that we're good in our eyes or in others' eyes, but good in the eyes of God.
People say, well, hey, preacher,
is this good?
Can I do this?
Well, have you read about it yet?
Well, no, I just want your opinion.
Well, my opinion.
Okay, well, get your Bible out.
Let's look at what God says about it.
Right?
It's like when someone Googles, hey, should I do this?
Listen, I'm a hypochondriac.
I go with that.
I am almost dead 4 times a week.
I'm for real serious.
Listen, I was laying in bed the other day.
had a pain right here.
Right there.
It was right, it was like the day after that workout that we did here on Saturday.
Had a pain right there, right there in that meaty spot.
And I was thinking, they going to take my gallbladder out.
I did.
I laid there.
I started, you know?
And then I was like, man, maybe it's not the gallblad.
Maybe it's my appendix.
And I sat there and I freaked out for real.
It's bad.
But you know what I didn't do?
I't Google it.
Because I've learned.
You are dead, right?
And that's what it tells me.
But what I'm trying to say is, listen, we got to stop going to others.
before we go to him.
I'm not saying you can't get good counsel from each other.
Always come to me.
But my counsel is going to be from him.
Else it's just opinion.
And so opinion can help a little bit, but opinion
can't get nothing done if it stays just opinion.
Is that is it making sense this morning?
When you are close to that, which is good, you
will find yourself far from that, which is evil.
See the girl, what does this mean for us?
Well, let me ask you, how do you love each other?
How do we love each other?
Is your love for your brothers
and sisters in Christ sincere?
Are hypocritical?
Listen, this hits home right here.
Do you only love
those who you like and agree with?
How
can we love those who need Jesus when we can't even love each other in the family?
of God.
What
is your relationship with evil?
Church,
we cannot fellowship with what God hates.
We
cannot partake in what he calls sin.
Why in the world?
Would we want to live in something that killed Jesus?
You do realize it was
our sin that caused God to send Jesus.
Therefore if we know that and believe that.
If we have a proper view of Calvary, how could we live in it?
Church, we cannot fellowship.
With what God hates, we must hold fast to what is good.
Let love be without hypocrisy.
Abhor what is evil.
Cling to what is good.
This morning, I just want to challenge us.
In a family our size and we're growing.
I believe it's a great crowd for Father's Day.
You know, in summer, we got a lot of families that are traveling and
going all sorts of places and stuff.
Got some people that are sick.
But in a church this
size, listen, it's easy when we're real small and we can control everything.
It's easy when a business meeting
is exactly what we want or it's easy when we get everything our
way because there's no one to argue with us about it.
It becomes difficult when God starts adding people.
It becomes difficult when new
personalities are input.
Differing opinions occur.
Maybe even different ways to get things done.
That is when it becomes difficult.
That's when we got to start loving each other.
In sincerity.
So maybe this morning, listen,
again, our family is growing and maybe you have some
bitterness or you have some resentment.
Maybe you have some hypocritical love towards somebody in this church right now.
You know, so often
we talk about a time of response, you know what we do?
Man, God, I know what you're telling me to do.
There's just no way.
Or God, you know what?
I don't want to have to get up in front of these people or I don't want to have to.
I know, okay, Lord,
I'll get it done.
Just...
Not right now.
You know what happens so often?
is a parable about this.
And see that God plants in your heart.
That conviction that the Holy Spirit has given you.
See, I
believe that we need to right now obedience.
Or right now, faith.
You know, every single time not right now, you know what happens?
don't do it.
And
so listen, I'm not looking for a big show.
I think it, let's not be, let's not be hypocrites this morning.
Let's be sincere about it.
But what I am looking for is for us
to be unified in God's word in such a way.
that we understand that we need to distance ourselves from that which is evil.
Cling to that which is good.
but also love each other in sincerity.
Whatever that means for you, I don't know.
But I know this.
It may look relationally different.
In other words, it may be a different person than it is for me than it is for you in
this, but the truth is the same.
So
it has bound eyes closed all over this place.
I just want to ask you.